{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "John Cutler attempted to discover a vaccination for this disease through human studies in Sing Sing Prison. Cutler also led an experiment where Juan Jos´e Ar´evalo allowed Guatemalans to be infected with this disease. This disease was given to participants in a study that claimed to treat “bad blood” to study its untreated progression, even after the discovery of penicillin. Spirochete bacteria spread, for ten points, what sexually transmitted disease that was given to African-Americans at the Tuskegee Institute?",
      "answer": "syphilis"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first person prosecuted under this legislation was Vermont congressman Matthew Lyon, and another of its targets was the Philadelphia Aurora. The Kentucky and Virginia Resolutions declared these bills unconstituional, and three of them were repealed when the Democratic-Republican Party came to power in 1800. For ten points, name this quartet of laws signed by John Adams in 1798 that enabled the government to expel foreigners and punish anti-government speech.",
      "answer": "Alien and Sedition Acts"
    },
    {
      "question": "This author is the title character of a J.M. Coetzee novel that centers on his excised chapter “At Tikhon’s.”Adreamaboutamanwhobeatsasicklyhorsetroublestheprotagonistofoneofhisnovels, who later encounters a man who commits suicide after saying that he is “going to America.” That protagonist by this author murders the pawnbroker Alyona Ivanovna, and eventually rediscovers Christianity with Sonya’s help. For ten points, name this creator of Rodion Raskolnikov, the author of Demons and Crime and Punishment.",
      "answer": "Fyodor Dostoyevsky"
    },
    {
      "question": "This event was precipitated by armed unrest led by the CGL during the “two red years.” U.S. Ambassador Richard Child gave tacit American approval of this event before it began, shortly after news of Gabriele d’Annunzio’s similarly planned event. Luigi Facta resigned in the wake of this event, whose leader remained in Milan in case it failed. For ten points, name this 1922 demonstration by tens of thousands of Blackshirts, the supporters of Benito Mussolini.",
      "answer": "March on Rome"
    },
    {
      "question": "In one of these conflicts, William Eaton led an expedition to capture Derna, and one ship ran aground by William Bainbridge was burned by the crew of the USS Intrepid. The USS Philadelphia was burned in the first of these conflicts by Stephen Decatur, and Decatur’s capture of the Meshuda during the second of these wars led to peace with Tunis, Tripoli, and Algeria. For ten points, name these early 19th century wars between the United States and a group of North African states.",
      "answer": "Barbary Wars"
    },
    {
      "question": "During the Asuka period in Japan, taxes were levied on this material and cotton. With gold and grain, it served as a currency during the Han Dynasty. A pathway associated with it was originally mapped by Zhang Qian [Jang-Chyen], and, through smuggling, Justinian’s Byzantine Empire acquired the means for this good’s production: mulberry seeds and the eggs of a certain worm. For ten points, name this fabric whose namesake “road” was a trade network linking China to Europe.",
      "answer": "silk"
    },
    {
      "question": "A decade after the Prague Spring, a similar event in this city was ended by the punishment of people involved in the April Fifth Incident. One man who ruled from this city was targeted by the never-executed Project 5-7-1. The Fifth Modernization was first posted in this city, where a Goddess of Democracy was erected during a 1989 protest put down by Deng Xiaoping. The Bird’s Nest Arena is located in, for ten points, what site of the 2008 Summer Olympics and Tienanmen Square, the capital of the People’s Republic of China?",
      "answer": [
        "Beijing",
        "Peking"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The term “Scissors Crisis” was coined by this man in response to a failure of the NEP. His forces supressed Stepan Petrichenko’s Kronstadt Rebellion. This man’s supporters established Fourth InternationaltocompetewiththeComintern. Thismancriticizedthenotionof“socialisminonecountry,” instead espousing a “permanent revolution,” but he was killed by a man with an ice pick while in exile in Mexico City. For ten points, name this Soviet politician who led the leftist opposition against Josef Stalin.",
      "answer": "Leon Trotsky or Lev Bronshtein"
    },
    {
      "question": "Lieutenant Ryan Philips flew the speaker in this event to the USS Abraham Lincoln. This speech commemorated the removal of a “grave threat” and liberation of “an oppressed people,” though Donald Rumsfeld attempted to edit its language. This speech, given exactly eight years before the death of Osama bin Laden, announced the end of “major” combat operations in Iraq. For ten points, name this 2003 speech delivered by President George W. Bush in front of a banner displaying a controversially triumphant phrase.",
      "answer": "Mission Accomplished speech"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Nazi concentration camps, this group was identified by a single purple triangle. The 1943 Barnette case established that this group could refuse to recite the Pledge of Allegiance. Founded by Charles Taze Russell, this group believes that 144,000 people will enter Heaven and practices a form of shunning known as “disfellowship.” Proscriptions against military service and blood transfusions are held by, for ten points, what non-Trinitarian Christian sect that publishes The Watchtower?",
      "answer": "Jehovah’s Witnesses"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The Treaty of Newport was one attempt to end this conflict. The Engagers took part in the Putney debates and were crushed at the battle of Preston during this war. Prince Rupert of the Rhine was decisively defeated at Marston Moor during this conflict, in which Pride’s Purge abolished the Long Parliament. Thomas Fairfax at Naseby opened, for ten points, what 17th century war that pitted Oliver Cromwell and Parliament against the royal forces of King Charles I?",
        "answer": "English Civil War"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Thomas Fairfax led this Roundhead, professional military force whose cavalry was called the Ironsides.",
        "answer": "New Model Army"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One side during this conflict conquered Colonia del Sacramento, but was forced to return it at the end of this conflict. The Duc de Villars won the Battle of Friedlingen during this conflict. The forces of Eugene of Savoy and the Duke of Marlborough won the Battle of Blenheim during this conflict. The Treaty of Utrecht ended, for ten points, what war that broke out in 1701 after Philip V became the king of a certain Iberian country?",
        "answer": "War of the Spanish Succession"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The War of the Spanish Succession broke out after the death of a Spanish king with this name. Another ruler with this name was known as “El Cazador” and was forced to abdicate in 1808.",
        "answer": "Charles or Carlos"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "John Paul Stevens wrote a 2014 New York Times editorial calling for the removal of this amendment from the Constitution. George Tucker applauded this amendment’s shift from language in the English Bill of Rights restricting its right to the wealthy, and the phrase “the People” in this amendment was held to apply to private citizens by Antonin Scalia in the 2008 decision D.C. v. Heller. The NRA holds that this amendment conveys an individual right. For ten points, name this constitutional amendment which bars infringing upon the right of the people to “keep and bear arms.”",
        "answer": "2nd Amendment to the U.S. Constitution"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The 2nd Amendment was officially incorporated in a 2010 case named for McDonald v. this city, where the death of Laquan McDonald in 2014 sparked massive protests.",
        "answer": "Chicago"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This composer wrote a Mass without woodwinds or low brass “for troubled times,” which gained its nickname from Napoleon’s defeat at the Battle of the Nile. This composer of the Lord Nelson Mass interrupted a quiet second movement with a sudden fortissimo chord in one work, and had performers leave the stage at the end of another work written for his patron, Prince Esterhazy. For ten points, name this “father of the symphony” who wrote the “Surprise” and “Farewell” symphonies.",
        "answer": "Franz Joseph Haydn"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Joseph Haydn’s E-flat concerto for this brass instrument was written for an experimental 5-key model invented by Anton Weidinger.",
        "answer": "trumpet"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During this event, Josefinas Hospital was destroyed by an incendiary bomb. This event was described for the London Times by George Steer. The aftermath of this event, which included eight separate waves progressing from heavy bombs, to machine gun strafing, to firebombs, was interpreted in a chaotic mural-sized artwork that shows a speared horse. For ten points, name this 1937 German bombing of a village during the Spanish Civil War, the subject of a large greyscale painting by Pablo Picasso.",
        "answer": "bombing of Guernica"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Guernica is a cultural center of this northern Spanish territory.",
        "answer": "Basque country"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "According to Richard Clarke, one holder of this position was to be ousted by Operation Orient Express. A former holder of this position was running for President of Austria in 1985 when his service in the Wehrmacht was uncovered. Another holder of this position died in a plane crash while en route to resolve the Katanga crisis. Kurt Waldheim and Dag Hammarskjold [hammar-sk’yold] have held, and Ban Ki-moon currently holds, for ten points, what position as leader of the United Nations?",
        "answer": "Secretary-General of the United Nations"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This diplomat from Ghana preceded Ban Ki-moon as Secretary-General and briefly served as a special envoy to Syria in 2012.",
        "answer": "Kofi Annan"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One Superintendent for these workers quarreled with Frederick Law Olmstead and required applicants to be “very plain looking” and at least 30 years old. Walt Whitman and Louisa May Alcott briefly served in this role. Henry Whitney Bellows led the U.S. Sanitary Commission, which mobilized these people and their supplies. Mary Edwards Walker earned a Medal of Honor for her work in, for ten points, what civilian role, also served during the American Civil War by Elizabeth Blackwell and Clara Barton, who founded the American Red Cross?",
        "answer": [
          "Union Army nurses",
          "any description of the medical profession, including doctor, surgeon, medic, etc."
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This advocate for the insane and founder of America’s first mental asylums served as the Superintendent of Army Nurses during the Civil War.",
        "answer": "Dorothea Dix"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This leader’s government accused five Bulgarian nurses of spreading HIV in a children’s hospital. This leader held the position of “Brother Leader and Guide of the Revolution.” In 2003, this leader accepted responsibility for the bombing of Pan Am Flight 103. This leader, who rose to power in 1969 after overthrowing King Idris, was overthrown by the National Transitional Council and killed during the Battle of Sirte during the Arab Spring. For ten points, name this colonel and long-time dictator of Libya.",
        "answer": "Muammar Gaddafi"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "270 people were killed due to the 1988 explosion of Pan Am Flight 103 over Lockerbie in this country.",
        "answer": "Scotland"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "The Confederacy",
      "prompt": "In the history of the Confederate States of America, name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Year in which it lost the Civil War.",
          "answer": "1865"
        },
        {
          "question": "First state to secede from the Union, where the first shots of the war were fired at Fort Sumter.",
          "answer": "South Carolina"
        },
        {
          "question": "Confederate general who surrendered to General Grant at Appomattox.",
          "answer": "Robert E. Lee"
        },
        {
          "question": "Confederacy’s first and only President.",
          "answer": "Jefferson Davis"
        },
        {
          "question": "Georgia park where those two aforementioned men, as well as Stonewall Jackson, are carved on the face of a rock dome.",
          "answer": "Stone Mountain"
        },
        {
          "question": "Union plan, devised by Winfield Scott, to blockade Confederate ports.",
          "answer": "Anaconda Plan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Confederacy’s first and only Vice President.",
          "answer": "Alexander H. Stephens"
        },
        {
          "question": "Captured British vessel on which James Mason and John Slidell tried to sail to Europe to gain international recognition for the CSA.",
          "answer": [
            "RMS Trent",
            "Trent Affair"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "French Monarchs",
      "prompt": "In the Ancient Regime, who or what was the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Despotic ruler known as the Sun King?",
          "answer": "Louis XIV"
        },
        {
          "question": "Queen executed in 1793 during the French Revolution?",
          "answer": "Marie Antoinette"
        },
        {
          "question": "First Bourbon king, who noted that “Paris is well worth a mass”?",
          "answer": [
            "Henry IV",
            "Henry of Navarre"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "House that often warred with France, whose Spanish branch included Charles V?",
          "answer": "Habsburg"
        },
        {
          "question": "Canonized king who launched the Seventh Crusade?",
          "answer": [
            "Louis IX",
            "Saint Louis"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "House that ruled between the Capetian and Bourbon houses?",
          "answer": "House of Valois"
        },
        {
          "question": "King who won the battle of Marignano and joined the Ottomans in the Unholy Alliance?",
          "answer": "Francis I"
        },
        {
          "question": "King known for his plotting that fought against Charles the Bold of Burgundy?",
          "answer": [
            "Louis XI",
            "Louis the Spider"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Middle Eastern Leaders",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Dictator who ruled Iraq during the Persian Gulf War and was overthrown in 2003.",
          "answer": "Saddam Hussein"
        },
        {
          "question": "Current Prime Minister of Israel.",
          "answer": "Benjamin Netanyahu"
        },
        {
          "question": "”Iron Lady” of Israel, its fourth Prime Minister.",
          "answer": "Golda Meir"
        },
        {
          "question": "Current President of Turkey.",
          "answer": "Recep Tayyip Erdogan"
        },
        {
          "question": "Former President of Egypt who was deposed in 2013 after claiming unlimited power to undo the work of his predecessor, Hosni Mubarak.",
          "answer": "Mohamed Morsi"
        },
        {
          "question": "Former President of Iran who spoke to the UN General Assembly in 2010, questioning whether the U.S. government committed the 9/11 attacks.",
          "answer": "Mahmoud Ahmadinejad"
        },
        {
          "question": "Current King of Jordan, who succeeded his father, King Hussein, in 1999.",
          "answer": "Abdullah II"
        },
        {
          "question": "Current Vice President of Iraq, who served as Prime Minister for 8 years after the end of the Transitional Government in 2006.",
          "answer": "Nouri al-Maliki"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This agency’s first head, retired General Hugh Johnson, advocated for a “blanket code,” and its Section 7a guaranteed the right of labor to collectively bargain. Charles Evans Hughes held that it overstepped the legislature’s Commerce Clause power in the (20 pts)",
        "“sick chicken” case. Until it was unanimously declared unconstitutional by the Supreme Court in Schechter Poultry Corp. v. US, this agency was promoted with a (10 pts)",
        "blue eagle and the slogan “We Do Our Part”. For ten points, name this New Deal administration that removed competition by setting prices and fair standards."
      ],
      "answer": "NRA or National Recovery Administration"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This empire’s only colonial possession, located in Tianjin, was granted in return for their meager participation in the Eight-Nation Alliance. The “Basic State Act” of this empire supposedly recognized all of its ethnic groups, although the status of languages as (20 pts)",
        "“customary” was often debated. This empire suffered embarrassingly large losses in the Brusilov offensive. A member of the Black (10 pts)",
        "Hand assassinated this empire’s Archduke Franz Ferdinand in 1914, provoking the First World War. For ten points, name this dual-monarchy led by the Hapsburg dynasty until its dissolution in 1918."
      ],
      "answer": "Austria-Hungary"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This river forms three sides of a rectangular shaped passage in the Ordos Loop and is the northernmost of the rivers whose headwaters are located in the Three Rivers Nature Reserve. In 1642, this river was forcefully flooded to halt a rebellion led by (20 pts)",
        "Li Zicheng near the end of the Ming Dynasty, which affected the cities of Xuzhou and Kaifeng. The tendency of this river to flood, carrying (10 pts)",
        "sediment from the Loess plateau, gives it the nickname “China’s Sorrow”. For ten points, name this Chinese river, named for the distinctive color of its silt."
      ],
      "answer": "Yellow River or Huang He"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The Lamfalussy process was used to develop the financial regulations used by this group. The third Delors Commission ratified the existence of this entity. The Copenhagen (20 pts)",
        "criteria are used to determine eligibility to join this group, and the Schengen Agreement allows for freedom of travel between members of this group. This organization was preceded by the (10 pts)",
        "ECSC and the EEC and was formally created by the 1993 Treaty of Maastricht. For ten points, name this organization of countries which includes France, Britain, and Germany."
      ],
      "answer": "European Union or EU"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This book was mostly financed by Wilhelm Wolff, who also was the dedicatee of the only volume of this work to be published during its author’s lifetime. A law describing the tendency of the rate of (20 pts)",
        "profit to fall was first described in this work’s Volume III, and it claims that class divisions came to be during a “primitive accumulation.” This work describes social relations and their transmutation into (10 pts)",
        "economic relations in its section on “commodity fetishism”. For ten points, name this analysis of the title economic concept, written by Karl Marx."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Das Kapital",
        "Capital"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One version of this game was coded for free by intern Wes Cherry. Another version of this game, as taught by Andr’e de Staercke, includes a “Devil’s Six” (20 pts)",
        "row. That version of this game was published as an app by former Secretary of Defense Donald Rumsfeld in 2016, was named for Winston Churchill, and uses two (10 pts)",
        "decks. The goal of this game is to move all cards from the field and deck onto four foundations, starting with the Aces. Klondike is a popular form of, for ten points, what single-player card game?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "solitaire",
        "Churchill solitaire before mentioned",
        "Klondike solitaire before mentioned"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One leader of this country proclaimed “death to the EPRP” and smashed bottles filled with blood on the floor. Supporters of Lij Iyasu were defeated at the Battle of Segale in this country. Captured British nationals in this country were freed by the forces of (20 pts)",
        "Robert Napier, leading to the suicide of Emperor Tewodros II. This country, which was once ruled by a communist junta known as the (10 pts)",
        "Derg, defeated Italian forces at the Battle of Adowa. For ten points, name this African country, once led by Emperors Menelik II and the Rastafarian messiah figure, Haile Selassie [HI-lah se-LAH-see]."
      ],
      "answer": "Ethiopia"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This work describes public credit as “a very important source of strength and security,” noting that “timely disbursements to prepare for danger frequently prevent much greater disbursements to repel it.” It describes a potential “formal and (20 pts)",
        "permanent despotism” “on the ruins of Public Liberty,” and it re-states the importance of neutrality in the ongoing war between (10 pts)",
        "France and Britain, despite an alliance with France. Foreign alliances and political parties are warned against in, for ten points, what address that opens with a decline to run for a third term as President in 1796?"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "George Washington’s farewell address",
        "descriptions"
      ]
    }
  ]
}